visitlisboa.com 2018-02-01

# | Visit LISBON

#### **PRIVACY POLICY**

**The Digital Visit Lisbon Platform comprises the website, mobile website version and mobile application (for Android and IOS).**

**The Visit Lisbon website, mobile website version and mobile application are jointly referred to hereinafter as the “Platform”.**

**Please read our Privacy Policy carefully before using the Platform.**

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) recognises, appreciates, complies with and defends your right to privacy, and, as such, has published this Privacy Policy, which rules on the collection and use of personal information via the Platform.

On using the Platform you agree to the collection and use of your personal information by the same, provided this is done in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You should access this Privacy Policy on a regular basis to ensure you are familiar with any amendments. If you are in doubt in relation to the Privacy Policy, you may contact us here. If you disagree with this Privacy Policy, you are not authorized to use the Platform and should exit immediately.

**Collection of personal information**

Non-registered users may only use the features of the Platform which do not require the user to be registered, whereby the following information is collected in relation to unregistered users of the Platform:

  * IP address;
  * cookies;
  * Google Analytics;
  * Geolocation;
  * Interaction with external social networks and platforms: Facebook, Twitter and Google+;
  * clicking-through.

Registered users are entitled to use all the features of the Platform, whereby the following information on registered users of the Platform is collected, in addition to that mentioned previously:

  * Personal information in the form of data inserted manually by the user, such as, for example, name, nationality, date of birth, interests, start and end date of the trip and people accompanying the user on the trip;
  * Facebook likes and interests;
  * Activities conducted and places visited (the places the user visits in person and the length of the stay);
  * Date of the use of the different features of the Platform;
  * Activities chosen / planned via the Platform;
  * Activities scheduled / reserved via the Platform, date of scheduling / reservation and the date on which the activity was conducted;
  * Use of the different features of the Platform and the activities chosen.

**Use of the personal information**

Users´ personal information is used to help users to plan their trips, obtain suggestions (tips on experiences and suggested itineraries) and to manage the activities they have decided to conduct, improving and enriching their experience of visiting Lisbon.

The Platform also uses users´ personal information for unnamed statistical processing with a view to the production of statistical reports, studies and analyses, with no way of individually identifying the users whatsoever. This processing of data and the development of models based on this information may be conducted by external suppliers, specifically the companies lostinthestars, lda and ebusiness ventures S.A. de C.V.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) does not provide the personal information collected from users of the Platform to any third parties in any manner whatsoever, neither free of charge nor in return for payment.

The statistical reports, studies and analyses produced based on the information collected by the Platform may be provided to third parties with no way of individually identifying the users whatsoever, either free of charge or in return for payment.

In the event the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) is legally obliged to cooperate with the legal or administrative authorities and is required to disclose the personal information of users of the Platform, it shall only provide the information requested or that which is justified within the scope of the judicial or administrative process. Users´ personal information may also be provided to the official authorities within the scope of a judicial or administrative process if this proves necessary in order to eliminate or reduce the criminal or civil liability of the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) or is to useful in the defence of its rights.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) has adopted security procedures to protect the personal information supplied by users of the Platform. Procedures are implemented to protect the personal information stored against unauthorised access, such as passwords and HTTPS security certificates, as well as technical and organisational measures to prevent the unauthorised or illegal processing of personal information and against the loss or destruction, including when accidental, of the same. The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) cannot guarantee the total security of the personal information supplied by users of the Platform.

The Platform is designed to be used by adults only, whereby in the event a person of under 18 years of age inserts personal information on the Platform this will only be used to contact this person directly to inform him/her that minors are not allowed to use the Platform.

You should use the settings in your personal account on the Platform to check and change the personal information supplied via the Platform user registration procedure, specifically to update or to correct incorrect data.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) reserves the right to alter this Privacy Policy at any time and at its sole discretion, whenever deemed necessary. If the alterations to the Privacy Policy seriously affect the personal information already obtained from the users of the Platform, the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) will take the measures it regards as reasonable and appropriate to notify these users of the changes to the Privacy Policy and off the option to alter or cancel their registration on the Platform.

**This Privacy policy applies equally to the website, mobile website version and mobile application comprising the digital Visit Lisbon platform.**

#### **TERMS AND CONDITIONS**

**The Digital Visit Lisbon Platform comprises the website, mobile website version and mobile application (for Android and IOS).**

**The Visit Lisbon website, mobile website version and mobile application are jointly referred to hereinafter as the “Platform”.**

**Please read these Terms and Conditions carefully before using the Platform.**

The Platform is the property of the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL), a private association of public use, enrolled with the Corporate Taxpayer Registry under Nº 501880160, headquartered at Rua do Arsenal, Nº 23, Lisbon, Portugal.

On using the Platform, users undertake to comply with the following Terms and Conditions and any changes to the same. You should access this Terms and Conditions on a regular basis to ensure you are familiar with any amendments. If you are in doubt in relation to these Terms and Conditions, you may contact us here. If you disagree with these Terms and Conditions, you are not authorised to use the Platform and should exit immediately.

**Intellectual property rights**

The entire text and image content of the Platform is published with protection of copyright, except text and image content which is already protected by third-party copyright.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) respects third-party intellectual property rights and requests all users of the Platform do likewise.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) reserves the right to file for legal action against the authors of any copy, reproduction or other unauthorised use of the content of the Platform.

**Use of the Platform**

ATL authorises the content of the Platform to be viewed and printed in accordance with the following conditions: (i) the content of the Platform may not be altered, (ii) removing or altering any notice of copyright, brand names or intellectual or industrial property rights featuring in the content of the Platform is prohibited, and (iii) as is the creation, exhibition, reproduction or distribution of work in relation to the content of the Platform.

Users of the Platform declare and guarantee that they will use the Platform in accordance with these Terms and Conditions and that they will not disrespect or breach the rights of any other party or fail to comply with any legal agreement or obligation with regard to other parties, or break any applicable law in force. Users of the Platform specifically agree to indemnify ATL for any third-party liability incurred, directly or indirectly, arising from their use of the Platform failing to comply with these Terms and Conditions. Users of the Platform guarantee to be of least 18 years of age and to possess the legal capacity to enter into this agreement and to use the Platform in compliance with all these Terms and Conditions.

Other requirements may exist for the use of certain functions of the Platform besides being 18 years of age or older.

Users may not register on the Platform more than once. Users of the Platform are required to keep their password confidential and are entirely responsible for any consequences arising from failure to keep their password confidential and the use of the same by third parties. Users are required to report any unauthorised use of their password or any shortcoming with regard to security to the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL).

Users of the Platform declare and guarantee that all the personal information supplied during the registration process as a user of the Platform is complete, accurate, up-to-date and true. Users of the Platform authorise Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) to check the veracity of the personal information collected and undertake to cooperate with the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) during such a check.

Users of the Platform declare and guarantee that all the information and content supplied during the use of the Platform:

  * is not fraudulent;
  * does not breach any copyright, brand names, patents or other intellectual or industrial property rights belonging to third parties;
  * does not breach any legal or administrative regulation;
  * is not defamatory, libelous, offensive or intimidating;
  * is not immoral, obscene or pornographic;
  * does not contain computer viruses or any computer files or programs which might damage, steal or in any other way interfere with the functioning of the Platform and its data in a negative manner;
  * does not create any direct or indirect links to content without having the right to establish such a link or to include such content;
  * is not a survey, poll or chain message.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) shall under no circumstances whatsoever be held liable for the information and content placed on the Platform by users which might in any way harm or compromise third parties. Moreover, the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) will immediately remove all information and content placed on the Platform by users which might raised doubt with regard whether it is harmful or damaging to third parties.

Furthermore, the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) shall not be held liable for any information and content on third-party websites to which the Platform redirects its users via direct or indirect links. The existence of a direct or indirect link to a third-party website neither means nor implies that the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) subscribes to or approves the information and content contained in the same, or is in any way bound to the same.

The use of the Platform is entirely free of charge, however it provides the opportunity to make purchases in the interest of and for the convenience of the users, Purchases may be made on the Platform, in the case of goods or services supplied or provided by the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL), or via direct links to third-party sites. When using direct links the purchases are made directly on the third-party site and not on the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) platform. This is not a contractual payment by the user, and serves only as the entity which provides the technical link to the third-party site. The user is entirely and exclusively liable for becoming familiar with the terms and conditions and privacy policy of third-party websites, in particular, contractual purchasing terms and conditions. On concluding a purchase on a third-party website, an agreement is entered into between the user and the website, whereby no such agreement is entered into between the user and the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL). Third-party suppliers of goods or service providers are independent business entities and are not associated with Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL), which, as such, cannot guarantee the satisfaction of the user in relation to the goods supplied or services provided. The user is required to take the care to gather the appropriate information on the purchase in question. The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) shall under no circumstances whatsoever be held liable for the goods and services supplied and provided by such third parties.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) is only liable for the sale of the goods and/or services supplied and provided in its name and on its behalf.

Users of the Platform declare to exonerate Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) from any charge, cost, expense, loss, damage or liability it might incur in any way in relation to the goods and services supplied and provided by such third parties.

The prices are specified in Euros and always include the applicable VAT, for both resident Portuguese taxpayers and taxpayers residing outside Portugal. The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) does not guarantee the infallibility of the information provide to users of the Platform with regard to prices and the availability of goods and services supplied and provided by third parties, due to the fact the updating of this information is not conducted in real time due to technical reasons.

Users will be asked to provide their credit card details during the purchasing process on the Platform. The personal information required for the transaction and the data in relation to the credit card is submitted directly to an approved payment services provider via an encryption protocol, whereby no third parties have access to the same. The credit card data will only be used by the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) to conduct the necessary procedure for the purchase or to issue a refund in the event of cancellation, when the user exercises the right to withdraw, or to report cases of fraud to the pertinent authorities, whereby such data is not stored on any server.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) reserves the right to cancel the registration of any user who breaches these Terms and Conditions, at any time, with no prior warning and without providing any justification, without prejudice to any civil or criminal proceedings which might take place.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) is not liable for any technical issues affecting the Platform, the causes of which are beyond the scope of intervention and responsibility of the Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL), and does not guarantee the uninterrupted availability of the Platform and the information and data, any may implement technical maintenance whenever it deems necessary.

**Trip Planner, What´s on, What´s nearby and Geo-Offers**

Among others, the Platform provides its users with the Trip Planner, What´s on, What´s nearby and Geo-Offers (geo-referenced offers) features.

Trip Planner is a feature on the Platform which registers interests of preference with a view to generating suggestions and personalised itineraries for the user.

What´s on is a feature on the Platform which enables the user to access a list of events in real time, presented by date.

The What´s nearby feature enables the user to filter attractions, restaurants and events by location, providing suggestions in accordance with where the user is at the time.

Geo-Offers is a feature on the Platform which enables users to view offers from associates of Lisbon Tourism, discounts and free entrances, providing suggestions in accordance with where the user is at the time.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) will make every effort to ensure the information provided to the users of the Platform is thorough and in the best interest of the users, however it cannot provide any guarantee, explicit or implicit, that all the information provided by the features of the Platform is always updated and accurate, and shall not be held liable if this should occur.

**Meet People – Social Traveling Lisbon**

This feature enables registered users to get to know and make contact with other tourists with similar interests by meeting at events or activities organized by the same, or at events and activities organised by the registered user, disclosing the same to other interested tourists.

This feature may not be used for political, religious, trade union or charity-related purposes.

The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) provides the Platform to enable its users to organise and participate in events and activities, but is totally alien to the decision to organise or participate in all events and activities, and is not required to oversee, accompany or monitor the same. Users should be prudent when deciding to participate in an organised event or activity and should pay strict attention to their privacy and safety before, during and after the same. The Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) will immediately remove or edit the disclosure of any event or activity created by a user which breaches these Terms and Conditions, with no prior warning.

In the event the user/organiser of the event or activity charges a fee for participation in the event or activity, Lisbon Tourism Association – Visitors and Convention Bureau (ATL) is completely alien to this fact, and does not receive all or part of this amount under any circumstances whatsoever. Users are required to be prudent when deciding to pay any amount requested to participate in an event or activity organised by other users via the Platform.

**These Terms and Conditions apply equally to the website, mobile website version and mobile application comprising the digital Visit Lisbon platform.**
